这是一个化油器，这是一个特殊的3D打印的透明化油器。
- This is a carburetor and this is a special 3D printed see-through carburetor.
这是一个高速摄像机，上面装着一个微距镜头。
And this is a high-speed camera with a macro lens on it.
你知道这是要干什么的。
You see where this is going.
如果你曾经启动过任何带有小型引擎的草坪护理产品，
If you've ever cranked some type of lawn care product,
你在某个时刻一定接触过化油器。
with a small engine on it,
you have interacted at some point with a carburetor.
问题是，这个小装置是做什么的？
The question is, what does this little device do?
是的，它混合空气和燃料。
Yes, it mixes air and fuel together.
但是怎么混合的呢？
But how? Like,
我想了解它是如何工作的。
I want to understand how it works.
作为一名机械工程师，
As a mechanical engineer,
直到有一天我去看望正在更换他的耕耘机上的化油器的父亲，我才意识到我对化油器的理解还不够。
I thought I had an understanding of carburetors until the day I went to visit my dad who was replacing a carburetor on his tiller.
我父亲是一个很好的老师，他对机械事物的工作原理有很深的理解。
My dad is a really good teacher and he has a really good understanding of how mechanical things work.
所以我决定放下我对化油器的所有认知，只请他从头开始教我。
So I decided to suspend everything I thought I knew about carburetors and just ask him to teach me from the ground up.
教我。
Teach me.
接下来是关于化油器的一切的45分钟课程。
What followed was a 45 minute lesson on everything about carburetors.
那是主喷射器化油器。
- That's the main jet carburetor.
看到侧面的孔了吗。
See the holes on the side.
碗里有汽油。
Bowl, you got gasoline in there.
- 嗯哼。
- Uh-huh.
- 浮子。
- Float.
看到针在那里上下移动了吗。
See the needle going up and down right there.
- 是的，先生。
- Yes, sir.
- 那是油门。你可以在那里看到。
- That's the throttle right there. You can see there.
节气门。
Choke.
我们在那里打开运行。
We running open right there.
吸力。
Suction.
当气缸下降时的进气。
The intake when the cylinder goes down.
- 它是一个真空。
- It's a vacuum.
- 它通过这里吸气。
- It sucks air through here.
把你的手指放在上面，
Put your finger up there,
真空会把这个直接吸开。
and the vacuum will pull this right open.
气缸中的阀门关闭，
The valve closes in the cylinder,
压缩行程上升，压缩汽油。
the compression stroke comes up and compresses the gasoline.
火花塞点火，将其推回下降。
The spark plug fires, pushing it back down.
（发动机转动声）
(engine turning)
运行平稳。
That's smooth.
工作良好。
Works well.
- 所以我父亲给了我一个关于化油器工作原理的大师级课程。
- So my dad gave me a masterclass in how carburetors work.
我要做的是尝试简要解释他教给我的内容。
What I'm going to do is try to explain in brief detail what he taught me.
然后我们将继续研究透明化油器，
And then we'll move on to the see-through carburetor,
我认为你可以更好地理解它。
where I think you can understand it a little bit better.
所以大多数化油器要么是铝制的，要么是热塑性塑料制的。
So most carburetors are either aluminum or thermoplastic.
那么让我们看看这里的铝。
So let's look at this aluminum here.
大多数化油器都有一些看起来很熟悉的东西。
Most carburetors have some things that all look familiar.
比如你有一些小的旋转装置在这里。
Like you've got some kind of little turny thing here.
在这边，你有另一个小的摇摆装置。
On this side, you've got another little floppy do.
如果你取下底部，
And down here, if you take off the bottom,
你可以看到底部有一种容器和里面的小东西，对吧？
you can see that there's some type of container on the bottom and a little thing on the inside, right?
所有这些看起来都很正常。
All this looks kind of normal.
就像如果你曾经看过发动机，
Like if you've ever looked at an engine,
你见过看起来像这样的东西。
you've seen stuff that looks like this.
热塑性塑料版本也是如此。好的。
The thermoplastic version kind of the same way. Okay.
所以我想让你注意的是，化油器有两个主要部分。
So what I want to draw your attention to is there's two main components to a carburetor. There's the top part.
顶部叫做文丘里。
And the bottom part, and the top part is called the Venturi.
底部叫做碗。
And the bottom part is called the Bowl.
为了理解这一点，
So in order to understand this,
我试图找到一个透明的化油器，我找到了两种不同的版本。
I tried to figure out if I could find a see-through carburetor and I found two different versions.
第一，我实际上在互联网上找到了一个透明的化油器。
Number one, I actually found a see-through carburetor on the internet.
问题是卖给我的那个人让我承诺不通过这个运行汽油。
The problem is the guy that sold it to me made me promise I wouldn't run gasoline through this.
这只用于教学，我是一个守信的人。
It was for teaching only, and I'm a man of my word.
所以我们不会通过这个化油器运行汽油。
So we're not going to run gasoline through this carburetor.
所以我不得不尝试找到其他来源的透明化油器，
So I was left to try to find other sources for see through carburetors,
我在互联网上找到了一个。
and I found one on the internet.
宾夕法尼亚州有一个年轻人。
There's a young man in Pennsylvania.
他创造了这个。
He created this.
这基本上是一个透明的文丘里，
It's basically a see-through Venturi,
是化油器的一部分，
which is part of a carburetor,
但它并没有完全做到我想要的，
but it didn't quite do what I wanted,
那就是展示化油器的完整内部工作原理。
which was to show the complete inner workings of the carburetor.
在这一点上，很明显，我们需要自己制造一个透明的化油器。
So at this point, it's clear,
we're going to have to make our own see-through carburetor.
记住，化油器有两个组成部分，对吧？
And remember there's two components of the carburetor, right?
首先，让我们谈谈文丘里管。
First, let's talk about the Venturi.
如果你像我一样，书架上有很旧的书，你可能会有一本详细解释化油器的书，它解释了文丘里管是一个非常酷的东西，你可以通过管道流动的液体。
If you are like me and you have really old books on your shelf,
you might have one that explains carburetors in great detail and explains that a Venturi is a really cool thing where you take fluid, that's flowing through a pipe.
如果你在某个点将管道收窄到更小的横截面积，那个点的静压会降低。
If you neck it down at some point to a smaller cross-sectional area, the static pressure at that point at the throat decreases.
这就在那个地方产生了一种真空效果。
Creating kind of like a vacuum in that one spot.
这可以用来将燃料吸入文丘里管。
Well, that can be used to suck fuel up into the Venturi.
化油器的文丘里部分是用来吸燃料进入管线的。
So the Venturi part of the carburetor is for sucking the fuel up into the line.
化油器的第二部分，油碗是用来储存燃料的。
The second part of the carburetor,
the Bowl is for holding the fuel.
经过大量的合作、交流和实际的工程会议后，
So after a lot of collaboration,
conversations and actual engineering meetings.
我们提出了一个3D打印的透明化油器解决方案。
We came up with a 3D printed solution for a see-through carburetor.
它由一个激光3D打印的外壳组成，
It consists of a laser 3D printed housing,
其中包括文丘里管和油碗。
which incorporates both the Venturi and the Bowl.
我们从Briggs and Stratton制造的热塑性化油器中移除了浮子和针。
And we removed a float and needle from a thermoplastic carburetor made by Briggs and Stratton.
我们激光切割了一个前盖，可以让你看到整个装置。
We laser cut our front cover that would allow you to see the entire thing.
然后我们用PLA塑料3D打印了一个节气门和油门杆。
And then we 3D printed a choke and throttle lever out of PLA plastic.
这就是3D打印的透明化油器。
So this is the 3D printed see-through carburetor.
在《Smarter Everyday》的早期一集中，
On an earlier episode of Smarter Everyday,
我描述了一个透明的引擎，我们实际上可以看到燃烧在气缸内发生。
I described a see-through engine and we actually get see the combustion happen inside the cylinder.
基本上，四冲程引擎有四个行程。
Basically there's four strokes to a four stroke engine.
你有进气行程，
You have the intake stroke,
这是它将燃油空气混合物吸入气缸的过程。
which is where it's pulling in fuel air mixture into the cylinder.
之后你有压缩行程，
After that you have the compression stroke,
它压缩燃油空气混合物。
which compresses the fuel air mixture.
然后你有火花塞处的点火，
And then you have the ignition at the spark plug,
它产生动力行程，推动活塞下行，
which creates the power stroke, driving down the piston,
然后顶部的阀门打开，你将排气从那个阀门推出，然后再次开始整个过程。
and then the valve at the top opens and you push out in the exhaust out of that valve and you start the whole thing over again.
你有进气、压缩、动力、排气。
You have intake, compression, power, exhaust.
进气、压缩、动力、排气。
Intake, compression, power, exhaust.
进气行程有趣的是它是一个真空状态。
The interesting thing about the intake stroke is that it is a vacuum. It is sucking air into the engine.
它将空气吸入引擎。
我们可以利用这一点。
And what we can do is we can take advantage of that.
跟我来，这有点复杂。
Hang with me. This is a little bit complicated.
这是化油器，假设引擎在右边，它利用进气行程的真空状态，使空气想要流向引擎。
So this is the carburetor and let's assume the engine is out here to the right it's taking advantage of the fact that the intake stroke has a vacuum and it makes air want to flow this way into the engine.
一旦空气开始这样流动，
So once air starts flowing this way,
空气就会从这边进来，开始在文丘里管那里收窄。
what happens is air comes in this side and it starts necking down into the Venturi there.
就像我们之前在书中说的，
Like we said, in our book earlier,
流动快的地方，压力就低。
where flow is high, pressure's low.
所以如果你在油碗下面有汽油，
And so if you have gasoline down here in the Bowl,
这里满满的，
down here, all full up right here,
你就有一根小管子，就像一根吸管，它上升并进入文丘里管的中心。
what you do is you have a little bitty of pipe right here,
like a straw that goes up and goes into the center of the Venturi.
这就会在这里产生一股小小的液体喷射，因为那个真空。
And what that does is that creates a little bitty jet of liquid that comes up right here because of that vacuum.
一旦发生这种情况，它就会混合，然后顺流而下进入引擎。
And then once that happens, it mixes and then it goes downstream into the engine like this.
所以基本上这边只有空气，
So basically you have nothing but air on this side,
你有燃料从这里上来。
you've got the fuel coming up here.
然后你有从这里开始的混合物。
And then you have the mixture that goes from here forward.
这基本上就是化油器的作用。
That's basically what a carburetor does.
节气门和油门在上面。
The choke in the throttle up top.
那些是我们之前展示的翻动的东西。
That's the flappy things we were showing earlier.
那是节气门，那是油门。
That's the choke and that's the throttle.
它们基本上是控制混合物进入引擎的。
Basically what they do is control the mixture that goes to the engine.
如果你关闭节气门，限制进入文丘里管的空气量，
If you close off the choke and you restrict the amount of air that goes down into the Venturi,
那么你可以创建所谓的浓混合物。
then you can create what's called a rich mixture.
意味着进入引擎的混合物富含汽油。
Meaning the mixture that goes to the engine is rich in gasoline.
如果你想启动引擎，它很难启动，你可能想这样做。
You might want to do that if you're starting the engine and it's having a hard time firing up.
如果你想让混合物变稀，
If you want to lean the mixture like this,
那意味着下游的混合物中汽油含量少。
that means the mixture downstream is lean of gasoline.
有不同的原因去做不同的事情。
And there are different reasons to do different things.
但如果你有一个理想的混合节气门，
But if you have an ideal mixed choke right here,
你全油门，
and you have full throttle,
那么你下游的化学反应会很好。
then you're going to have great chemistry downstream.
这会让引擎运行得非常快。
It's going to make the engine run really, really fast.
这些是大多数化油器都有的两个控制装置。
So these are the two controls that most carburetors have.
这基本上是化油器可以存在的最简单设计。
And this is basically the simplest design for a carburetor that can exist.
让我们去找爸爸，让他教我们如何使用这个装置，看看我们是否能慢动作捕捉到它。
So let's go get dad to show us how to use this thing and see if we can catch it in slow motion.
首先我们要做的是实际上将燃气管连接到化油器。
The first thing we had to do is actually hook the gas line up to the carburetor.
好的，我要打开燃料。
[F] Okay, I'm going to open the fuel.
开始了。
Here goes.
它会自己填满的。
[D] And it'll just fill up.
应该会的。
[F] It should.
啊，它在做了。
[D] Ah, it's doing it. [Destin sounds surprised]
[笑] 我不知道为什么。
[laughs] I don't know why.
你不知道碗是用来做什么的吗？
[F] Didn't you know that's what the Bowl was for?
不，我不知道会发生这样的事。
[D] No, I did not know that was what was going to happen.
嗯，是的。
[F] Well, yeah.
我的意思是，现在你这么做了，很明显。
[D] I mean it's obvious, now that you do it.
燃料流进这里，当浮子开始浮动，
Fuel flows in here and when the float starts to float,
它会移动这个针，
it moves this needle,
针会压入座位并停止燃料流入碗。
which presses into the seat and stops the flow of fuel into the Bowl.
所以你总是有正确的量。
So you always have the right amount.
现在回火是个问题。对吗？
Now backfiring is an issue. Right?
是个问题。
[F] It is an issue.
那么，怎么样了？
And how about getting this.
准备好了吗？
[D] Ready to go?
是的。因为我们几分钟前洒了一些汽油。
[F] Yeah. Cause we spilled some gasoline a few minutes ago.
所以，如果回火发生了，如果我理解正确的话，
[D] So if, if a backfire happens, if I understand correctly,
火会向后冲回化油器，我们没有对这个化油器进行压力测试。
fire's going to come backwards back into the carburetor and we did not pressure test this carburetor.
对。
[F] Right.
所以这个可能会爆炸，所有这些汽油可能会着火，围绕我们。对吗？
[D] So this this could explode and all this gas could be on fire and go around us. Right?
希望不会。
[F] Hopefully not.
[两人笑]
[Both laughing]
事实上，稍微打开门，让地板上的任何蒸汽都出去。
As a matter of fact, open the door just a little bit to let whatever vapors here on the floor, go out.
好的。
[D] Okay.
准备好了吗？
[F] Ready?
是的。
[D] Yeah.
(发动机启动)
(engine cranking)
哦，我看到一些蒸汽。
Oh, I saw some vapor.
你看到了吗？
[F] Did you?
在进气冲程上。是的。
[D] On the intake stroke. Yeah.
我们会看到的。
We're going to see it.
啊，它在运行。
Aah, it's running.
好的，我触发了[高速摄像机]
Okay I triggered [the high speed camera]
我们可以关闭它。
We can kill it.
关闭它？
[F] Kill it?
是的，关闭它。
[D] Kill it, yeah.
你可以看到进气口的蒸汽。
You can see the vapor in the intake.
你能看到吗？
[F] Can you?
是的，你可以。
[D] Yeah you can.
你看到了吗？
Did you see it?
没有。
[D] No.
你怎么会没看到那个。
[D] What do you mean you didn't see that.
我在找火。
[F] I'm looking for fire.
[两人笑]
[Both laughing]
好的。你抓到了吗？
Okay. Did you catch it?
我不知道。我觉得，我按了按钮。
[D] I don't know. I think, I hit the buttons.
它运行得很丰富。它在咕噜咕噜地响。
[F] It was running rich. It's sputtering, sput, sput, sput.
所以我打开了油门，这样它就可以稀释混合物，它开始平稳运行。
So I open the choke up so it lean out the mixture and it started running smooth.
就像它实际上应该被使用的那样。
[D] Like it. Like, it was actually supposed to be used.
嗯，是的，它应该这样工作。
[F] Well yeah, that's the way its supposed to work.
我不知道这里会有泡泡和东西。
I didn't know there'd be bubbles and things here.
[Destin拍打他的爸爸]
[Destin smacks his Dad]
哦，看那个！
[D] Oh, look at that!
看那个！
[F] Look at that!
你看到了吗？
[D] You see it?
是的。
[F] Yep.
[每次你看到汽油流进发动机时都会有快速射击声]
[rapid firing sounds each time you see the gas flow into the engine]
[器乐音乐]
[instrumental music]
[液体在慢动作中穿过室内]
[The fluid rushing through the chamber in slow motion]
你可以看到空气，空气-燃料混合物进入燃烧室。
[F] You can see air, air-fuel mixture going in the combustion chamber.
这是进气。
[D] This is intake.
不，进气是...
[F] No intake is...
是当它在吸入时。
[D] Is when it's sucking in.
对。
[F] Right.
进气。
[D] Intake.
是的。
[F] Yeah.
[F] Yes.
是的。
[F] Better?
[D] Way better.
点火。
[D] Fire.
进气阀关闭。
[F] Intake valve closes.
关闭排气行程。
[D] Closes exhaust stroke.
是的。
[F] Yes.
再次进气。
[Both] Another intake.
对。
[F] Right.
[D] Volumetrically.
对。
[F] Right.
你能用一个化油器跑两个汽缸吗？
[D] So can you run two cylinders off of one carburetor?
哦，可以，可以。或者三个或四个。是的。
[F]Oh yeah, yeah. Or three or four. Yeah.
真的吗？
[D] Really?
[D] Are you serious?
真的吗？
[D] Really?
好的。
[D] Okay.
化油器所做的就是混合燃料和空气，你有一个化油器可以运行八个汽缸。
[F] The carburetor, all it does is mix fuel and air and yeah,
you got one carburetor that runs eight cylinders.
它运行得非常快吗？
[D] So it's running really, really fast?
每个汽缸吸入它能使用的东西并燃烧它。
[F] Each cylinder sucks in what it can use burns it.
Sucks in only what it can use.
我的摩托车每个汽缸都有一个化油器，你必须平衡它们。
Now my motorcycle has a carburetor for each cylinder and you have to balance those.
因为如果你有一个，一个因为得到不同的而打击更重。
[D] Because if you have one,
one that's hitting harder because it's getting a different.
对，它根本不会平稳运行。
- Right. It won't run smooth at all.
用一个化油器运行多个汽缸的优势是你可以得到相同的化学计量混合物。
[D] So the advantage of running multiple cylinders off of one carburetor,
is you get the same Stoichiometric mixture throughout.
你可以看到节流阀后面的涡流。你看到了吗？
[D] You can see the vortex behind the throttle.
Do you see that?
你能？哦，是的。是的。
[F] You can?
Oh, it is. It is.
湍流是一个涡流湍流。
Turbulent flow is a vor, vortices turbulence.
是的，绝对是。
[D] Yeah, absolutely.
你只是想让我激动，因为你知道德里克可能会看这个视频。
You're just trying to get me riled up,
cause you know, Derek might watch this video.
是的。我喜欢德里克。
[F] Yeah. I like Derek.
[D] I like Derek too.
你现在会对这个设计做什么改变？你会改变什么？
would you change on this design? Like now?
What would you change?
我会让控制更加僵硬，这样当你把它们放在位置上时，它们会自己保持。
[F] I would make the control stiffer so that when you put them in position,
they would hold themselves.
发动机会吸开油门。是的。
[F] The engine sucks the throttle open. Yes.
哦，是这样吗？
[D] Oh does it?
它会失控。如果你不物理上限制它，它会越来越快。
[F] It does. run away.
If you don't physically restrain it,
它会失控。如果你不物理上限制它，它会越来越快。
it gets faster and faster and faster.
没有调速器。是的。
[F] There's no governor. Yes.
它试图拉开它，我把它固定在那里，因为我不想让它失控。
It's trying to pull that open and I'm holding it there so that it does not because I don't want it to [D] Run away.
你感觉这个移动有多困难吗？
[F] You feel how tough it is to move this?
是的。
[D]Yes.
它很难移动，这是故意的。
[F] It's difficult to move on purpose.
我现在更理解化油器了。
[D] I understand carburetors now.
是的。我的意思是，我猜没有人真正百分之百理解它。
Yeah. I mean, I guess nobody actually a hundred percent understands it.
我不能做我想做的事。我不能让它运行，因为它不会保持它的设置位置，但是，天哪，它工作了。
[F] Well I couldn't do what I wanted to do.
I could not make it run because it wouldn't hold its setting position, but man, it works.
所以当你全开时，它会全速运行吗？
[D] So when you just went wide open, would it run wide open?
我不想让它失控。
[F] Well, I didn't want it to run away.
试试看。
[D] Try it.
我们有灭火器。
We got a fire extinguisher.
你有离心力。你会撕毁发动机。你可以跑得太快。
- Well you got centrifugal forces.
You tear the engine up. You can run way too fast.
你有调速器。你有油门。你在工厂制造的化油器中有控制，但我们这里没有。
You've got governors. You got throttles.
You got control in a factory built carburetor that we don't have here.
你可以，你可以。
You could get, you could.
我可能会受伤。
[D] I could get hurt.
我们可能会把引擎弄得四分五裂。
[F] We could tear the engine all to pieces.
好的。
[D] Okay.
通过提供更多的动力，它会运行得比设计速度还要快。
[F] By supplying more, it'll run faster than it's designed to run.
你能放大那个吗？
Can you zoom into that?
是的，先生。我可以。
[D] Yes sir. I can.
我可以换一个更紧的镜头，这样我们就能放大，看到燃料进入文丘里，然后我们可以看到它蒸发。
I can get a tighter lens so we can zoom in and we can see the fuel come up into the Venturi and then we can it vaporize.
然后被吹散。被吹散。
[F] And get blown away. Get blown away.
你想这么做吗？
[D] You wanna do that?
是的。
[F] Yeah.
让我们以你觉得舒服的速度稳定运行它。
[D] Let's run it steady state as fast as you're comfortable.
我会尽量这么做，但我做不到。
[F] I'll try to, but I can't.
我得在这里放一根手指。
I'm going to have to put a finger right there.
我认为现在不用节气门就能启动。
I think it'll just start right now without a choke.
用手指还是‘fenger’？
[D] With a finger or fenger?
‘fenger’。
[F] A fenger.
[Destin笑了]
[Destin laughs]
[引擎运转]
[engine running]
好吗？
[F] Okay?
明白了。
[D] Got it.
[引擎咕噜声]
[engine sputtering]
[引擎停止]
[Engine stops]
差点熄火。
[D] Almost kill it.
那是个好化油器。
[F] That's a good carburetor.
[器乐音乐]
[instrumental music]
[随着进气冲程吸入混合气，响亮的风声]
[Loud wind rushing sounds as the intake stroke pulls in the mix]
所以燃料正在进入喷嘴。
[D] So the fuel is coming up into the jet.
那是主喷嘴，对吧？
That's the main jet, right?
它是从哪里进入的，就在那里？
[F] Where's that entering, right there?
是的。它直接从文丘里中间上来，然后进气吹过。
[D] Yes. It's coming straight up in the middle of Venturi and then the intake blows [F] Air.
吹过空气。
[D] blows air across it.
看看下面那些东西在跳舞。
Look at all the stuff dancing down there.
让我们再运行一次，
Let's run it again,
只看油碗顶部的燃料。
and just look at the top of the fuel in the Bowl.
我只想看看那看起来是什么样子。
I just want to see what that looks like.
(引擎启动)
(engine starting up)
机械振动比我预期的要剧烈得多。
The mechanical oscillations are way more violent than I expected.
引擎在那里运行得相当快。
[F] The engine is running pretty fast right there.
你看到的每一次抖动都是一个冲程，不是吗？
Each time you see a shake is a stroke, isn't it?
不，我不这么认为。
[D] No, I don't think so.
你不这么认为？
[F] You don't?
我认为那是一种振动模式。我认为那是一种谐振。
[D] I think it's a vibration mode. I think it's a harmonic.
你认为那是个音叉？
[F] You think it's a tuning fork?
我认为是。
[D] I do.
应该有四个。
[F] There should be four.
应该是进气、压缩。
Should be intake, compression.
动力冲程。
[D] Power stroke.
动力冲程，排气。
[F] Power stroke, exhausts.
是的。
[D] Yes.
所以每个应该有四个冲程。
[F] So should have four strokes for each.
如果你仔细看的话，确实有。
And you do have, if you're look at it right there.
上止点和下止点。
Top dead center and bottom dead center.
你对一个乡巴佬来说相当聪明。
[D] You're pretty smart for a redneck.
嗯，这就是为什么他们称它为四冲程。
[F] Well, that's why they call it four stroke.
[两人笑了]
[both laughing]
好的。所以现在我们对化油器有了宏观上的理解。
[D] Okay. So now we understand the carburetor on a macro level.
我们已经构建了一个功能性的化油器，这太棒了。
We have built a functioning carburetor, which is awesome.
但现在我们需要做的是，我想看看细节。
But now what we need to do is I want to see the tight stuff.
当那股燃料喷射上来，进气口从上面吹过时，那是什么样子？
Like what happens when that jet of fuel comes up and the air intake comes over the top of it?
那看起来是什么样子？
What does that look like?
[引擎运转]
[engine running]
明白了。
[D] Got it.
哦。
Ooh.
[笑]是的，我知道。
[Laughing] Yeah, I know.
[器乐音乐]
[Instrumental music]
它是悬浮的。
[F] It's suspended.
一滴燃料悬浮在空中，然后吸力来了，把它全部打碎。
A drop of fuel was suspended in the air and then suction comes and breaks it all up.
Derek会喜欢这个的。
Derek is gonna to love that.
[两人笑了]
[Both laughing]
因为湍流。
[D] Because of turbulence.
是的。这里的层流也变得太湍流了。
[F] Yes.
There's change in the laminar coming in here, too turbulent.
哦。
Ooh.
汇聚发散喷嘴。
[D] Converging diverging, nozzle.
所以化油器就是一个火箭喷嘴。
It. So a carburetor is just a rocket nozzle.
It's a rocket nozzle. Is what it is.
我的意思是你正在加速。
I mean you're speeding up.
小心，哦哦哦哦。
[F] Watch it. Oh, oh, oh, oh.
有点下降，是的。
[D] It's a little drop and [F] Yeah.
化油器试图做的是在分子层面上增加表面积，对吧？
Carburetor tries to do is increase the surface area on a molecular level. Right?
你是什么意思？
[D] What do you mean?
为了实现完全而彻底的燃烧，你需要尽可能多的燃料表面积。
[F] In order to get full and complete combustion,
you need all the surface area that you can get of the fuel.
因为理想情况下，你有一个氧分子紧挨着一个燃料分子。
[D] Because ideally you have an oxygen molecule right next to a fuel molecule.
所以现在我要看看当你第一次拉绳子时会发生什么，当化油器里没有燃料时，到燃料进入时。
So now I'm going to get what happens right when you pull the rope for the first time,
when there's no fuel in the carb to when fuel goes in.
我要看看那是什么样子。
I'm gonna see what that looks like.
发动机运转。
[Engine running]
明白了。
[D] Got it.
发动机咕噜咕噜的响。
[Engine sputtering]
从某处进了些空气。
[F] Getting some air from somewhere.
有趣的是我们几乎关不掉它。
[D] It's fun that we almost couldn't turn it off.
有一点点风险。
There's a little bit of risk.
永动机。
[F] Perpetual motion machine.
两人大笑。
[Both laughing]
哦，看这个。
[D] Oh, look at this.
什么？
[F] What?
在进气冲程这里，你看到了绳子。
[D]So on the intake stroke here, you see the rope.
这太酷了。
How cool is that?
你可以看到前景中的绳子，还有化油器。
You can see the rope in the foreground and you see the carburetor.
我无法想象像这样的镜头。
I could not have imagined a shot like this.
哇哦。
[F] Oh wow.
是的。
[D] Yeah.
帕姆，帕姆，帕姆。
[F] Pam, Pam, Pam.
是时候用铝来铣削这些了，我想。
[D] Time to a time to mill those out of aluminum, I think.
那是PLA，所以我打赌PLA是被汽油分解的，
That's PLA, so I bet that PLA is getting broken down by the,
因为它一开始并不那么脆弱。
[F] By the gasoline.
Because it wasn't that flimsy to begin with.
你可以看到燃料在吸管和喷嘴中上升。
[D] You can see the fuel coming up in the,
in the straw and the jet.
看那个。你可以看到，
Look at that. You can see,
你能看到。
[F] You can.
看到那里的流动。
[D] See that the flow right there.
你可以看到一切。
You can see everything.
对于下一个镜头。我们想看看我们是否能够通过Venturi的喉咙拍摄高速。
For the next shot. We wanted to see if we could shoot the high speed down the throat of the Venturi.
所以特伦顿跳进来帮忙，因为我们需要更多的手。
So Trenton jumped in to help because we needed more hands.
只需弹出油门。
Just pop the choke out.
然后我们就直接看下去。
And then we're just gonna look straight down the barrel.
我会把油门弹出大约四分之三，至少一半。是的。
[F] I'll pop the choke about three-fours,
or at least half of it. Yeah.
好的。那会让我们的混合物变稀，对吧？
[D] All right. So that's going to lean our mixture, right?
是的。
[F] Yep.
你在调焦吗？
[D] Are you pulling focus?
一旦它运行起来，我就得这么做。
[T] I'm going to have to once it's running.
是的。
[D] Yeah.
发动机运转。
[Engine running]
你得用手指去测量。
[F] You're going to have meter with your finger.
是的。
[D] Yeah.
所以我会用手指去测量，你抓住油门。
So I'll meter it with my finger and you grab the throttle.
油门现在是全开的，
Throttle is wide open right now,
但它会自动关闭。
but it shuts off automatically.
所以如果你抓住它，然后把它推回去，那会保持在那里。
So if you'll grab it and shove it back the other way that will keep it there.
那边？
[F] That way?
保持在那里，是的。
[D] Keep it there, yeah.
发动机高速运转。
[Engine running at high speed]
我可以用我的拇指来控制油门。
[D] I can literally throttle it with my thumb.
笑声。
[Laughs]
来吧。
[T] Come on.
是的。
[D] Yeah.
好的，等一下。
Okay, hold on.
我无法集中注意力，因为你的拇指在干扰我。
[T] I can't focus because of your thumb.
准备好了吗？
[D] Ready?
好的。
[T] Yup.
[T] Okay.
发动机声音变得更响、更快了。
[Engine running louder/faster]
你拍到了吗？
[D] Did you get it?
我想是的。
[T] I think so.
发动机开始咕噜作响。
[Engine sputtering]
发动机，去死吧！
[D] Die engine!
我不希望你有任何，哦，我得到它了。
I don't want you to have any, oh, I'm getting it.
哦，我的天哪。发动机终于停了。
Oh my goodness. [Engine finally stopped]
看，那是你的蒸汽。
[F] There's your vapor. There's your vapor.
[F] There's your vapor right there.
我看到蒸汽了。
[D] I saw the vapor.
对，就是那里，那是蒸汽。
Whoa that's, that's vapor.
是的。
[F] Yep.
好的，所以蒸汽消散了。
[D] Okay. So [F] Vapor go away.
刚才发生了什么，爸爸在启动它，我用手捂住了它，我把它闷住了。
- What just happened, is dad cranked it I covered, I choked it with my hand.
他在操作油门。
He was operating throttle.
那一刻我们是，我们是在共鸣。
For a second there we were. We were vibing.
是的，我们是疯了。
[F] Yeah, we were insane.
（笑声）
(laughing)
所以我在操作节气门。爸爸在操作油门。
[D] So I was running choke. Dad was running throttle.
特伦特在试图构建镜头。
Trent was trying to frame the shot.
哦！！哈哈哈，我刚打到你的麦克风了。
OhHHHHHHHH!!   hohoho I just hit your mic.
它使得掉落变平。
It flattens the dropout.
它确实如此，它确实如此。
[F] It does, it does.
它使得掉落变平，并且将其分散。
[D] It flattens the dropout and it distributes it.
看它！
Look at it!
（器乐音乐）
[Instrumental music]
[Instrumental music continues]
（慢动作枪声和空气呼啸声）
[Gunshot in slow motion air whooshing sounds]
我现在对化油器如何吸入空气与主喷嘴上升的燃料相互作用有了三维的理解。
[D] I now have a three-dimensional understanding of how a carburetor intake air interacts with fuel coming up in the main jet.
这是值得的。
[F] That was worth it.
这段旅程始于我简单地询问爸爸化油器是如何工作的。
[D] This journey started by simply asking my dad how carburetors work.
通过亲手制作和操作一个化油器，
And by taking the time to build and operate one by hand,
我们了解到化油器的设计简单却非常复杂。
we learned that the design of a carburetor is simple yet very complex.
而且其中的流体动力学非常美妙。
And the fluid dynamics at play are downright beautiful.
所以我知道很多时候当你看到视频中的广告部分时，人们会选择点击离开。
So I know a lot of times when you get to the ad portion of a video, people kind of like click away.
他们会想，哦，我对此不感兴趣。
They're like, oh, I'm not interested in that.
但我想告诉你为什么我选择与这个特定的赞助商合作，为这个特定的视频。
But I want to tell you why I chose to work with this particular sponsor for this particular video.
当我看到一个复杂的概念，比如化油器，
When I look at a complicated concept, like a carburetor,
这是一个非常难以理解的东西。
that's a very difficult thing to understand.
所以我喜欢做的一件事是我喜欢制作手工模型，通过玩弄所有的变量来理解正在发生的事情，
So one thing I like to do is I like to build hands-on models and understand what's going on by playing with all the variables and getting to the point where I have a fundamental understanding of the concepts.
好了，这个视频的赞助商是Brilliant。
Well, the sponsor for this video is Brilliant.
Brilliant是一个网站和应用程序，提供超过60门课程，内容丰富且互动性强。
Brilliant is a website and app that has over 60 courses with hands on interactive content.
这样你就可以理解像数学、
So you can understand really interesting topics like math,
科学、计算机科学等非常有趣的话题。
science, computer science, all kinds of stuff.
这是一种动手实践的学习方式。
This is a hands-on approach to learning.
这是我的大脑的工作方式。
And this is the way that my brain works.
Brilliant有一个我已经开始的非常有趣的课程。
Brilliant has a really interesting course that I've started.
这是一个Python课程，
It's a Python course,
它不同于仅仅阅读一本书并进行例子练习。
and it's different than just reading a book and going through examples.
你实际上有一个在线的动手编码盒子，你可以在盒子里操纵概念，
You actually have an online hands-on coding box and you can manipulate the concepts in the box and you can write code for yourself and troubleshoot it.
看，我在学习。
There you go.
All right. So I'm learning.
我对此感到兴奋。
I'm excited about it.
所以如果你想尝试这个，
So if you would like to try this,
去看看所有的课程。
go to check out all the courses.
他们有逻辑、特殊相对论等方面的内容，
They have stuff in logic, special relativity,
无论你有兴趣学习什么。
whatever you're interested in learning.
这将帮助你理解概念，直到你对手头的话题有了理解。
This will help you go through and understand the concepts to the point where you have an understanding of the topic at hand.
我认为你会喜欢它。
I think you'll enjoy it.
所以去看看吧。Brilliant.org/SmarterEveryDay，
So go check it out. Brilliant.org/SmarterEveryDay,
免费注册。
sign up for free.
还可以在高级会员资格上获得20%的折扣。
Also get a 20% discount on the premium membership.
我喜欢动手实践的学习方式。
I like to learn in a hands-on fashion.
如果你在看这个视频，很可能你也是。
If you're watching this video, chances are you do too.
我认为你会非常喜欢它。
I think you'll really enjoy it.
所以请访问Brilliant.org/SmarterEveryDay。
So Brilliant.org/SmarterEveryDay.
我希望你喜欢和我一起学习化油器。
I hope you enjoyed learning about carburetors with me.
这是一个奇妙的装置，非常有趣。
This is a fantastic device. It's interesting.
正如我父亲所说，化油器有它的不足，
The carburetors suck as my dad says,
但你得到了文丘里效应，你有了碗室。
but you get the Venturi, you got the bowl.
我就是很喜欢理解事物是如何工作的。
I just really like understanding how things work.
我希望你也喜欢这个过程。
And I hope you enjoyed that as well.
随意订阅。
Feel free to subscribe.
如果你觉得这个视频值得订阅，
If you feel like this video has earned it,
如果不是，也没关系。
if not, that's no big deal.
我认为你会喜欢看第二频道，我可以和父亲更深入地交谈，当他向我解释一切时，你可以看到我脑海中灯泡亮起的时刻，父亲是个伟大的老师。
I do think you would enjoy seeing the second channel where I get to talk to my dad in greater detail and you get to see the light bulb come on in my mind as he explains everything to me, dad's a great teacher.
随意去第二频道看看。
So feel free to go check that out on the second channel.
如果你对此感兴趣，可以订阅。
Feel free to subscribe. If you're into that.
如果不感兴趣，也没关系。我很高兴你在这里。
If not, no big deal. I'm just glad you're here.
我想感谢所有支持Smarter Every Day的赞助者，让我能够做我自己喜欢的主题，我很感激你们。
I want to say thanks to all the patrons for supporting Smarter Ever Day let me do topics that I enjoy myself and I'm grateful for you.
总之，就是这样。
Anyway. That's it.
我是Destin。你在Smarter Every Day变得更聪明。
I'm Destin. You're getting Smarter Every Day.
祝你有美好的一天。再见。
Have a good one. Bye.
你怎么看，爸爸？
What do you think dad?
[父亲] 我认为这是一项大工程。
[F] It's a lot of work. That's what I think.
坐在键盘前阅读评论时，我觉得这并不像我原本想象的那么有趣。
It's not as fun as what I thought it would be from a distance when I'm sitting at the keyboard and reading the comments.
但拍摄视频很有趣。
It's fun.
我甚至不想想剪辑。
But taking the video shots,
I don't even wanna think about editing.
我认识的人中没有几个能说他们从零开始制作过化油器。
Not many people that I know can say that they have made a carburetor from scratch.
[父亲] 我不会说这是从零开始。
[D] I wouldn't necessarily call this scratch.
[儿子] 但现在那些真正从事小型发动机工作的人可以给你提供比你听到的更专业的信息。
[F] But now people who actually work on small engines could give you a lot more educated words than what you're getting.
[父亲] 我不想要一个专门修理小型发动机的人。
[D] I don't want a person that is paid to work on small engines.
我想从我父亲那里学习化油器。
I want to learn about carburetors from my dad.
[笑声]
[Laughs]
[儿子] 你可以随便在街上找个人。
[F] You could have picked anybody going down the street.
[父亲] 我认为你做得很好。
[D] I think you're doing all right.
[儿子] 并且得到更多的信息。
[F] And got more information.
[父亲] 我认为你做得很好。
[D] I think you're doing just fine.